Ahmad Ali

Full-stack Developer - London, UK. Portfolio: https://ahmad-ali.co.uk/

Email: ahmad.ali.uk14@gmail.com • phone: 07383164194 • GitHub: https://github.com/ahmad-ali14

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmad-ali-07383164194/

SUMMARY

I'm a Full-Stack Developer with 2 years of experience. I assist in teaching a full-stack javascript course at CodeYourFuture. I'm educated up to degree level and I've finished more than 35 online courses. I'm currently studying computer science at UoPeople university. And I used to be a pharmacist.

EXPERIENCE

Code Your Future, London—Full Stack Developer

April 2020 - PRESENT

- Full teaching day each sunday.
- Lead 3 graduates on their final project.
- Assist maintaining the school tech infrastructure.
- Stack: JS: React, Redux, Node, MongoDB, Docker, AWS, CircleCI
- This is a volunteering position.

Self-Employed, London — Freelance Developer

April 2019 - PRESENT

- Worked with few start-ups in the UK and abroad.
- Provided a wide range of services covering building and hosting websites, bug fixes, basic SEO services, DB services ...
- Customized wp themes and plugins, build online shops ...
- Stack includes: TS/JS, PHP, WP, WP_API, React, Node, Redux, GoLang, Heroku, AWS, MongoDB, MySQI ...

Pharmacist, Syria— Baylasan Pharmacy

Nov 2016 - April 2018

- Registered prescribing pharmacist. Community pharmacist and medical representative.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

- I Believe In Science, Lebanon Science Translator Arabic / English 2018 2019
- MW-LABS, Syria Freelance Social Media Marketer 2014 2016

SKILLS

- Js/Ts, React-Node, MongoDB, MySQL, Html, CSS, bootstrap, jquery
- Rest API, git, npm, Docker, Php, WordPress, WP API.
- Sequalize, Formik, Material UI, Redux, Redux sagas, Golang, python, heroku, stripe, gocardless, AWS ...
- Responsive web design, eCommerce, money-handlers integration.

PROJECTS

- Hex Luxury LTD April 2020 https://hexltd.co/
- Roye Interiors LTD December 2019 https://royeinteriors.com/
- **Lesvos Forms** september 2020 https://central.ahmad-ali.co.uk/ (demo)
- Bike Change Guru September 2020 https://www.bikechange.guru/
- Code Your Future April 2020 https://codevourfuture.io/

Details and other projects are on my website https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/projects

EDUCATION

University of The People, USA — Bachelor Computer Science 2020 - 2023 (exp)

- Online, part-time. Will not affect my job.

Kiron Open Higher Education, Germany — Associate Degree in Computer Science **2018 - 2020**

- Give their students access to online courses, which I finished 35 of 100 courses.
- More here: https://kiron.ngo/en/about-us/

Free Code Camp, Online — Full Stack Developer BootCamp 2019

- More here: https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn

Damascus University, Syria — Bachelor degree in pharmacy and pharmaceutical chemistry **2011-2016**

- Some courses: analytical chemistry 1-2-3, biotechnology 1-2, bioinformatique ...

RECENT ONLINE LEARNING

- Introduction to Software Product Management, University of Alberta Coursera.
- Algorithmic Toolbox and data structures, University of California San Diego Coursera
- List of all courses here: https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/#online-education